<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kiona Weisel, MSc | Protect Lab</title>
    <link>/en/author/kiona-weisel-msc/</link>
      <atom:link href="/en/author/kiona-weisel-msc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kiona Weisel, MSc</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Protect Lab 2022</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/en/author/kiona-weisel-msc/avatar_hue94adabfb9cc5e27ea06e3274885a5b9_928338_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Kiona Weisel, MSc</title>
      <link>/en/author/kiona-weisel-msc/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Study Shows Limited Effects When Mental Disorders are Only Treated with Smartphone Apps</title>
      <link>/en/post/apps-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/post/apps-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The number of available apps for mental health is steadily increasing in the app stores. In principle, apps could be a low-threshold, anonymous, time- and location-independent and cost-effective supplement to traditional mental health treatment options, but their effectiveness is still largely unclear.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recently published systematic review, Kiona Weisel et al. examined the effectiveness of smartphone apps as a stand-alone treatment for mental health. The meta-analysis included randomized controlled trials that examined apps for the treatment of adults with increased symptoms of mental disorder compared to a control group. A total of 19 studies with 3681 participants were found with apps to improve depression, anxiety disorders, alcohol consumption, smoking, post-traumatic stress disorder, sleep disorder and self-harming thoughts and behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results showed that smartphone apps had only small effects on depression and smoking behavior, whereas there were no effects on anxiety, self-harming thoughts and behaviors and alcohol consumption. Individual studies with apps for post-traumatic stress disorder were also not effective, while large effects were found in two individual studies on sleep problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps have enormous potential, but the current study situation is sobering. The approach must be fundamentally distinguished from web-based treatment formats for mental illness, for which numerous studies show that they can have great effects on a wide range of mental illnesses, many of which are even comparable with those of conventional health care services such as pharmacotherapy or psychotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion: Smartphone apps cannot be recommended as a stand-alone treatment for mental disorders on the basis of the current evidence. If affected persons are interested in digital care services, they should resort to well-studied web-based offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-019-0188-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to the article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICare Prevent</title>
      <link>/en/project/icare-prevent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/icare-prevent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental stress is not uncommon. Many people suffer from low spirits, worries, fears, or feel a general sense of dissatisfaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7-week online training ICare Prevent provides help in dealing with such feelings and offers background information on how they arise. In addition, the training aims to improve mental well-being and reduce mental discomfort through systematic training of helpful and proven strategies such as problem solving and activity planning to strengthen important areas of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online training ICare Prevent is currently being evaluated in a multicenter study in cooperation with universities in Germany, Switzerland, the Netherlands, Spain and Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICare Prevent is part of the EU-funded Horizon 2020 program, which has set itself the goal of developing, implementing and evaluating online training for the prevention and treatment of mental disorders in order to improve existing care structures, open new access routes and overcome implementation barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-coordination&#34;&gt;Project Coordination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the direction of Dr. David Ebert, Prof. Dr. Thomas Berger and PD Dr. Michael Schaub, one focus of our research at the Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy (KliPs) at the University of Erlangen-Nuremberg and at the Universities of Bern and Zurich is the development and scientific investigation of online programs in various areas, such as depression, anxiety disorders, stress management, sleep disorders, alcohol abuse and procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promotion--cooperation&#34;&gt;Promotion &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICare Prevent is a cooperation project within the framework of the ICare - Integrating Technology into Mental Health Care Delivery in Europe project. ICare Prevent received funding within the Horizon2020 research and innovation program of the European Union (Grant agreement No 634757).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICare project aims to establish an innovative, comprehensive mental health care delivery model in Europe. It combines evidence-based prevention, early detection and treatment of common mental disorders via a common online platform. In cooperation with established health care providers, ICare will complement or be integrated into existing services in order to avoid and reduce long-term costs caused by mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project partners come from a total of six European countries (Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Great Britain, Netherlands, Spain). All project partners have many years of research experience in the field of e-mental health. Together they can present a portfolio of more than 30 evidence-based online programmes for the promotion of mental health and for prevention, self-help, treatment and aftercare of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://icareprevent.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;banner.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
