<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Protect Lab</title>
    <link>/en/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/en/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Protect Lab 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/en/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>StAR</title>
      <link>/en/project/star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development and Evaluation of an online- and mobile based Intervention for adolescents and young adults with PTSD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PTSD is a mental disorder, which can occur after witnessing a traumatic event. The disorder can affect  emotional, physical, social as well as academic development. It&amp;rsquo;s concequences can, especially for children, adolescents, and young adults, extend into adulthood. The elevated distress, the possible psychological implications, educational difficulties as well as possible long-term suffering within the disorder can result in a high burden on an individual as well as on a societal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are effective treatments for PTSD in adolescents and young adults, not every person affected receives treatment offering due to structural as well as attitudinal barriers. Internet- and mobile-based interventions can help fill this health care gap. But they do not yet exist for adolescents and young adults so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project StAR aims to fill this research- as well as the health care gap, in developing an internet- and mobile-based Intervention for adolescents and young adults with PTSD and evaluating it in a feasibility study. A subsequent randomized controlled trial aims at determining its efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StAR is a subproject in the research association BestForCan. BestForCan aims at disseminating a special psychotherapeutic intervention for children, adolescents, and young adults after child abuse and neglect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_ee96c4f2b625e9e08e5927806375e8c5.png 400w,
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_41659f3d5883de3b3d423ba65a023caf.png 760w,
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_ee96c4f2b625e9e08e5927806375e8c5.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;79&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dried Blood Spots</title>
      <link>/en/project/dried-blood-spots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/dried-blood-spots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modification of biomarkers through an internet-based intervention for depression in back pain patients on sick leave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is a serious psychological condition that can have a devastating impact on patients, their family, friends and society. There is currently no laboratory test for this disorder, so patients often have to wait years for a diagnosis. During this time they do not receive the treatment and support they need. For this reason, we are developing a molecular test based on &amp;ldquo;Blood Spots&amp;rdquo; (i.e. dried drops of blood on filter paper). Such a test can provide an early and accurate diagnosis for patients with depression and help to get further assistance quickly. We measure the concentration of over 100 proteins in the dried blood drops. To do this, we use a technique called mass spectrometer analysis. The results of the study will be published.
​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_bae4c81deef1712e40303c825245869e.png 400w,
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_c6ef50dccb1886f16a4e144b3f73e361.png 760w,
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_bae4c81deef1712e40303c825245869e.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;92&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Compared</title>
      <link>/en/project/e-compared/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/e-compared/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is one of the most common and serious diseases of our time. Currently, about four million people in Germany suffer from the symptoms, but only a few receive effective treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet-based forms of treatment can be a possible supplement to classic therapy concepts. These promise a lower uptake threshold, reduced waiting times and help independent of time and place. Numerous studies show that these forms of treatment can be successful in depression. However, not all patients are interested in and/or suitable for a purely internet-supported treatment. Combined procedures that combine psychotherapy on site and internet-supported treatment elements could use the advantages of both approaches and be a promising supplement to classic forms of therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against this background, the Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy of the FAU is investigating the effectiveness of such a combined depression treatment (online lessons on website, smartphone app, personal therapy conversations on site in Erlangen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruitment in general practitioners&#39; practices within the RCT study took place from February 2015 to August 2016. We are currently not enrolling any more patients in the study. The treatment phase of &amp;ldquo;Moodbuster&amp;rdquo; will be completed in early 2017 for the last patient enrolled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scientific-background&#34;&gt;Scientific background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-COMPARED (European-COMPARative Effectiveness research on online depression) is an interdisciplinary project involving specialists from the fields of psychology, health technology, communication and information technology and health care. The original project period from 01.01.2014 to 31.12.2016 has been extended by another 6 months until 30.06.2017. The project compares the standard treatment of depression in eight European countries with a combination of personal (face-to-face) and web- or mobile-based therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evaluation will use randomized controlled trials (RCT), advanced ICT (information and communication technology) platforms, technological intelligence and an economic prediction model to investigate which form of treatment is more effective, for which patient group and under which conditions. In Germany, the evaluation study was implemented in primary health care and thus in the setting of the outpatient treatment of depressive patients in GP practice. For this purpose, close cooperation with GP practices in the Erlangen-Nuremberg-Fürth metropolitan region took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cooperating-gp-practices-in-the-metropolitan-region-erlangen-nuremberg-fürth&#34;&gt;Cooperating GP practices in the metropolitan region Erlangen-Nuremberg-Fürth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank the GP practices who, as cooperation partners, have been able to support the study and win over their affected patients to participate in the study on the treatment of depressive symptoms. Flyers and posters for the waiting room and the personal doctor-patient consultation were made available to the GPs for the recruitment of patients in the GP practices. The time spent by the general practitioners involved in the study was to be a maximum of 30-60 minutes per patient and was compensated. By participating in the study, family doctors&#39; practices are making an important contribution to the further development of depression treatment in Germany. In addition, their patients benefited from a prompt start of treatment; i.e. therapy places were available without waiting time. An overview of the cooperating GP practices can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psych1.phil.uni-erlangen.de/forschung/internetbasierte-therapie/e-compared_hausrztliche_kooperationspartner_2016.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-research-project-for-depressive-patients-in-family-practice&#34;&gt;The research project for depressive patients in family practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients affected by depressive symptoms could contact their own family doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice, as any family doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice could start a cooperation with us at any time. By answering a health questionnaire (by post or online) patients registered with us and subsequently received further information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conditions-of-participation&#34;&gt;Conditions of participation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients who were at least 18 years old and were not undergoing any current psychotherapeutic treatment by psychologists or doctors were eligible to participate in the study. Previous therapeutic experience or an existing or concurrent drug treatment was allowed. Another prerequisite for participation was the diagnosis of major depression (mild, moderate or severe; also chronic courses or relapses). Patients with the diagnosis of a minor depression were referred to a depression prevention study by us. The diagnosis was carried out by our test directors (telephone interview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to participate in our study, the treating family doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice had to already be a cooperation partner of ours or show willingness to become one. In order to participate in the internet-supported therapy modules, a computer with internet access was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The project was awarded the Erlanger Medizinpreis in 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Union&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_0a6daedd5d42b552fd5eb150f074859b.png 400w,
               /en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_0ae680500a00e1d62804ae75d5c51b31.png 760w,
               /en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_0a6daedd5d42b552fd5eb150f074859b.png&#34;
               width=&#34;122&#34;
               height=&#34;82&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.Back</title>
      <link>/en/project/get-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/get-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effectiveness of a guided web-based intervention for the treatment of depression and back pain during incapacity to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back pain and depression are among the number one common diseases and are enormously stressful for those affected. Depression usually affects all areas of the patient&amp;rsquo;s life: thinking, feelings, actions, body and relationships with other people. And because it is precisely with this disease that it is so difficult to make the decision to seek help, even though the drive to change something is lacking, it is extremely important to take a new path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why an online training has been developed for people who have back pain, suffer from depressive symptoms, are currently on sick leave, and want to work on improving their mood. The following questions will be examined:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Get.Back effective for back pain patients with depression compared to standard treatment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Get.Back cost effective for back pain patients with depression compared to standard treatment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which factors moderate the effect of Get.Back?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on a two-arm, pragmatic, randomized controlled study, Get.Back aims to investigate a web-based depression intervention. Get.Back includes modules for behavioral activation, problem solving, cognitive restructuring, physical activation and relapse prevention. The program is developed for weekly treatment over a total period of nine weeks and includes stwo booster sessions two and four months after the end of treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary study outcome is depression severity at end of intervention. Secondary outcomes are: Depression remission, quality of life, pain intensity, pain-related limitation, pain-related self-efficacy, work capacity, adherence and satisfaction with the intervention, and intervention costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outlook: The present effectiveness study focuses on disability due to back pain and depression as the most common health conditions associated with high life expectancy and health care costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.barmer.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BARMER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_6e2bf0050d56d7fe291b17cc6fcc1c94.png 400w,
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_b8f812ff84836ee00aa5937edf443e1e.png 760w,
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_6e2bf0050d56d7fe291b17cc6fcc1c94.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;86&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICare Prevent</title>
      <link>/en/project/icare-prevent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/icare-prevent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental stress is not uncommon. Many people suffer from low spirits, worries, fears, or feel a general sense of dissatisfaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7-week online training ICare Prevent provides help in dealing with such feelings and offers background information on how they arise. In addition, the training aims to improve mental well-being and reduce mental discomfort through systematic training of helpful and proven strategies such as problem solving and activity planning to strengthen important areas of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online training ICare Prevent is currently being evaluated in a multicenter study in cooperation with universities in Germany, Switzerland, the Netherlands, Spain and Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICare Prevent is part of the EU-funded Horizon 2020 program, which has set itself the goal of developing, implementing and evaluating online training for the prevention and treatment of mental disorders in order to improve existing care structures, open new access routes and overcome implementation barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-coordination&#34;&gt;Project Coordination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the direction of Dr. David Ebert, Prof. Dr. Thomas Berger and PD Dr. Michael Schaub, one focus of our research at the Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy (KliPs) at the University of Erlangen-Nuremberg and at the Universities of Bern and Zurich is the development and scientific investigation of online programs in various areas, such as depression, anxiety disorders, stress management, sleep disorders, alcohol abuse and procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promotion--cooperation&#34;&gt;Promotion &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICare Prevent is a cooperation project within the framework of the ICare - Integrating Technology into Mental Health Care Delivery in Europe project. ICare Prevent received funding within the Horizon2020 research and innovation program of the European Union (Grant agreement No 634757).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICare project aims to establish an innovative, comprehensive mental health care delivery model in Europe. It combines evidence-based prevention, early detection and treatment of common mental disorders via a common online platform. In cooperation with established health care providers, ICare will complement or be integrated into existing services in order to avoid and reduce long-term costs caused by mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project partners come from a total of six European countries (Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Great Britain, Netherlands, Spain). All project partners have many years of research experience in the field of e-mental health. Together they can present a portfolio of more than 30 evidence-based online programmes for the promotion of mental health and for prevention, self-help, treatment and aftercare of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://icareprevent.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;banner.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Balance With Us</title>
      <link>/en/project/mit-uns-im-gleichgewicht/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/mit-uns-im-gleichgewicht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental disorder prevention with Internet- and telephone-based interventions for persons in the &amp;ldquo;green professions &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model project &amp;ldquo;Mit uns im Gleichgewicht&amp;rdquo; (In Balance With Us), funded by the Social Insurance for Agriculture, Forestry and Horticulture (SVLFG), aims to promote and maintain mental health among farmers, foresters and horticulturists and is being scientifically evaluated by the Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-Nuremberg and the University of Ulm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain and promote the mental health of farmers, foresters and horticulturists, the SVLFG offers the insured persons on-site preventive measures such as seminars on stress management. Within the framework of the model project, these offers will be expanded to include internet and tele-based interventions (online health training by the GET.ON Institute and intensive individual coaching by IVPNetworks). Interventions to prevent mental stress are particularly in demand in agriculture, as this occupational group is exposed to many stressors and strains due to difficult working conditions (e.g. high workload, family conflicts, seasonal work). It has been proven that internet and tele-based interventions can be effective, but the effects at population level depend on the actual use of the target group. With this background, there is a great need for scientifically sound knowledge about the needs of farmers, foresters and horticulturists, their partners and family members working with them, and how these needs can be met effectively. In addition, it should be examined whether target group-specific offers for this group of people can effectively and cost-effectively counteract the development of depressive disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy of the FAU, on behalf of SVLFG, is investigating in partly overlapping sub-projects the current use and acceptance of preventive interventions among farmers, gardeners and foresters on the one hand, and the effectiveness of two specific interventions (online-based health training, telemedical intensive care) on the other hand. In addition, the new health services and online-based interventions are being offered to SVLFG insured persons via different access routes as part of a large implementation study throughout Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target group of the project&lt;/strong&gt;
Farmers insured with SVLFG, their co-insured partners and family members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project duration&lt;/strong&gt;
01.06.2017 – 30.05.2021&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paivina-Care</title>
      <link>/en/project/paivina-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/paivina-care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paivina-Care is an online-based self-help training that is specially designed to meet the needs of women with Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder. The training is offered free of charge as part of a scientific study at the Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuremberg (FAU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder is also known as vaginismus or dyspareunia. Women with Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder suffer from difficulties and pain during vaginal insertion, so that sexual intercourse is no longer possible for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder is a combination of two different diagnoses of female sexual dysfunction. The new diagnosis includes both symptoms of sexual pain disorder (dyspareunia) and penetration disorder (vaginismus).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WARD-BP</title>
      <link>/en/project/ward-bp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/ward-bp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet-based Prevention of Major Depression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major Depression (MD) is associated with a significant loss of quality of life, increased mortality rates and enormous economic costs. It is estimated that current therapies could reduce the burden of disease attributable to MD at the population level by only one third. Preventive services can help reduce the burden of disease caused by MD. The aim of the study is therefore to evaluate an internet-based intervention for the prevention of MD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: In a two-arm randomized controlled trial (N=420) the (cost-) effectiveness of an internet-based intervention (GET.ON Depression) relative to a control condition (psychoeducation) will be compared to the 12-month catamesis. The sample includes adults with subclinical depression. GET.ON Depression includes minimal therapeutic support by an online coach. The primary endpoint is the time to onset of a depressive episode. A &lt;a href=&#34;/en/health-economics/&#34;&gt;health economic evaluation&lt;/a&gt; from a societal perspective will be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bmbf.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Ministry for Education and Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_2a1a4076e4ffb17b060d8250b4bea5ea.png 400w,
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_c7f1d6fb5e7b40bab347bfc90f8a1bc9.png 760w,
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_2a1a4076e4ffb17b060d8250b4bea5ea.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;145&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Offline</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-offline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GET.On Offline is an online-based self-help training for coping with problematic internet usage. Problematic Internet usage can relate to computer games, social networks, but also to online sex, online shopping and online gambling. Where is the line between everyday use and problematic use? Problematic behavior begins when affected persons have an irresistible desire for the respective activities. Their thoughts and emotions are massively influenced by online offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who use the Internet excessively begin to lose control over their use and, if they are denied access, withdrawal symptoms may occur. This can manifest itself, for example, in restlessness, nervousness or depressive mood. Tolerance can also develop and other important areas of life can be affected. Problematic Internet use thus has negative consequences in various areas. One may no longer pay attention to a healthy lifestyle or experience losses in professional or academic areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geton-training.de/internetsucht-php/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Study Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;hek.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImpleMentAll</title>
      <link>/en/project/implementall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/implementall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;projektbeschreibung&#34;&gt;Projektbeschreibung&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In den letzten zwei Jahrzehnten wurden große Anstrengungen in die Entwicklung, Testung und Implementation von eHealth für eine weite Bandbreite von Gesundheitsproblemen, im körperlichen wie im psychischen Bereich gesetzt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nichtsdestotrotz schaffen es wenige Interventionen in die Routinebehandlung, oder benötigen viele Jahre auf dem Weg dahin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ImpleMentAll (IMA) zielt darauf ab, durch die Entwicklung, Anwendung und Evaluation maßgeschneiderter Implementationsstrategien in einem natürlichen Labor derzeitiger eHealth-Implementationsintiviativen in der EU und darüber hinaus eine evidenzbasierte Antwort auf dieses Problem zu geben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Forschung des Projektes baut dabei auf vorhergegangenen internationalen Projekten auf (z.B. &lt;a href=&#34;https://renewinghealth.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Renewing Health&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.e-compared.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;E-COMPARED&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastermind-project.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MasterMind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.implementall.eu/16-npt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NPT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.implementall.eu/17-nomad.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NoMAD&lt;/a&gt;, und &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.implementall.eu/18-mast.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MAST&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die laufenden Implementations-Initiativen, die die Basis für die Implementationforschung dieses Projektes bilden, basieren sämtlich auf internet-basierter kognitiver Verhaltenstherapie (iCBT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICBT-Implementationsprozesse werden derzeit auf der ganzen Welt durchgeführt. ImpleMentAll nutzt diese Projekte, um Werkzeuge zur Implementation von iCBT zu entwerfen, die eHealth effizienter machen sollen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ziele-des-projekts&#34;&gt;Ziele des Projekts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entwicklung eines generischen &amp;ldquo;Integrated Theory&amp;rdquo;-basierten Rahmens für Interventions-Anpassungen (ItFits-toolkit) zur datenbasierten Implementation evidenzbasierter eHealth-Dienstleistungen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstration der Vorteile des ItFits-toolkit auf die Implementation von eHealth für psychische Störungen (iCBT) in 9 europäischen Ländern und Australien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dissemination des validierten Toolkits in verschiedenen Kontexten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StudiCare</title>
      <link>/en/project/studicare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/studicare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health-promotion-in-college-students&#34;&gt;Mental Health Promotion in College Students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StudiCare includes various online training courses for the prevention and treatment of mental illness, tailored to the needs of college students. In order to improve existing offers, the StudiCare panel regularly surveys undergraduate students at the Friedrich-Alexander-University and the University of Ulm about their mental well-being from the first semester onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College is a new stage of life in which students make the transition from adolescence to adulthood. This transition period is characterized by joyful experiences as well as new, stressful situations. These include, for example, looking for one&amp;rsquo;s own apartment, organizing finances and studies, finding new friends, getting used to a new environment, exam stress, etc. In the course of their studies, students are not only confronted with this new situation, but may also experience crises. In combination with possible risk behaviors, such as excessive consumption of alcohol or cannabis, this can lead to exhaustion, psychosomatic complaints, anxiety and depressive disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;studicare-panel&#34;&gt;StudiCare Panel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web-based panel survey is conducted in numerous countries worldwide as part of the WHO The World Mental Health Survey Initiative under the coordination of Harvard University among students from the first semester onwards. The aim of the survey is to obtain information on the mental health of students as well as on risk and protective factors for emotional stress during their undergraduate studies. In addition, more information on the willingness and barriers to using psychosocial interventions and counseling services will be collected. With information from the surveys, the need for help and support services will be assessed, existing counseling services will be improved and new online-based interventions tailored to the individual needs of students will be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;studicare-online-health-trainings&#34;&gt;StudiCare Online Health Trainings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online health training courses from StudiCare are low-threshold structured self-help training courses. These trainings can improve the well-being of students and alleviate complaints in a wide variety of areas. They can be used independently of time and place, can be optimally integrated into the individual daily routine and can be conducted anonymously. In the training courses, students manage their complaints independently by working through numerous modules. Modules are based on cognitive-behavioral techniques that are also used in conventional psychotherapy. Essential here are various practical exercises such as relaxation techniques, protocols for self-observation and the integration of small exercises into everyday life (&amp;ldquo;tiny task&amp;rdquo;). These help to reduce negative behavior and build up positive behavior. In the course of the project, new trainings are continuously being developed that deal with topics that are relevant for students. The newly developed online health trainings will be examined in randomized clinical studies to evaluate their effectiveness and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.studicare.com&#34;&gt;Training Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evidence-based-methods-for-promoting-mental-health-among-students-series-of-meta-analytical-reviews&#34;&gt;Evidence-based methods for promoting mental health among students: Series of meta-analytical reviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to derive appropriate measures, a comprehensive assessment of the current evidence base of psychosocial support services is necessary. In a series of meta-analytical reviews, the current knowledge about effective psychological treatment and prevention services including their effectiveness is collected and critically examined. Psychological interventions and their effectiveness are examined with regard to specific disorder areas (e.g. anxiety symptoms, eating disorders, sleep disorders, suicidal tendencies) or intervention methods (e.g. internet-based procedures, &amp;ldquo;third wave&amp;rdquo; procedures). Along with clinical effectiveness, special attention is devoted to the influence of interventions on the academic impairment of students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promotion--cooperation&#34;&gt;Promotion &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER, Bergische Universität Wuppertal, European Union, FernUniversität in Hagen,
FOM University, Harvard Medical School, Leuphana University of Lüneburg, Minddistrict, RWTH Aachen University,
University Jaume I, University of Ulm, University of Zurich, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam,
World Health Organization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;logos.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;501&#34;/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Diabetes</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-diabetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-diabetes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet-based intervention for major depression in diabetes mellitus type 1 and type 2 with smartphone support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 30% of all diabetes patients suffer from major depression or subclinical depressive symptoms. Meta-analyses prove the effectiveness of internet-based health interventions (IGI) in the area of depressive disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a randomized controlled trial, participants with diabetes (type 1 and type 2) and depressive symptoms (N=352) are assigned to a six-week diabetes-specific Internet-based program for managing depressive symptoms or to a control group (psychoeducation) with unrestricted access to routine care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily text messages and weekly individual feedback by e-mail are intended to increase the adherence of the training. The primary endpoint is the reduction of depressive symptoms. Secondary endpoints include diabetic-specific emotional stress and glycaemic control (HbA1c).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Program effectiveness and cost-effectiveness will be assessed after the intervention and at 3, 6, 9 and 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/geton-diabetes/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png 400w,
               /en/project/geton-diabetes/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_3201281d5628750d711e0a83c4b19c50.png 760w,
               /en/project/geton-diabetes/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/geton-diabetes/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;121&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Mood Enhancer</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-mood-enhancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-mood-enhancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet-based prevention of major depression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major Depression (MD) is associated with a significant loss of quality of life, increased mortality rates and enormous economic costs. It is estimated that current therapies could reduce the burden of disease attributable to MD at the population level by only one third.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preventive services can help reduce the burden of disease caused by MD. The aim of the study is therefore to evaluate an internet-based intervention for the prevention of MD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: In a two-arm randomized controlled trial (N=420) the (cost-) effectiveness of an internet-based intervention (GET.ON Depression) relative to a control condition (psychoeducation) will be compared to the 12-month catamnesis. The sample includes adults with subclinical depression. GET.ON Depression includes minimal therapeutic support by an online coach. The primary endpoint is the time to onset of a depressive episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A health economic evaluation from a societal perspective will be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/geton-mood-enhancer/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png 400w,
               /en/project/geton-mood-enhancer/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_3201281d5628750d711e0a83c4b19c50.png 760w,
               /en/project/geton-mood-enhancer/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/geton-mood-enhancer/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;121&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Panic</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-panic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-panic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online training for the management of panic disorders with smartphone support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet-based interventions (IBI) to reduce panic and fear have proven to be effective. So far, however, these online programs have not supported the person concerned in practicing new behavioral patterns directly in the fear-inducing situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this purpose we developed GET.ON Panic - an online training based on cognitive behavioral therapy consisting of 6 lessons on psychoeducation, exposure, cognitive restructuring and relapse prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training has been expanded with elements for the smartphone, such as a diary or exposure app. In a 2-arm randomized controlled study, the effects of GET.ON Panic are compared with those of a waiting control group. Participants with subclinical and clinical panic disorder (with and without agoraphobia) are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GET.ON Panic is a promising IBI, which, thanks to smartphone support, starts &amp;ldquo;where the panic happens&amp;rdquo; - namely in the everyday life of those affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/geton-panic/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png 400w,
               /en/project/geton-panic/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_3201281d5628750d711e0a83c4b19c50.png 760w,
               /en/project/geton-panic/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/geton-panic/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;121&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Regeneration</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online regeneration training for better sleep for teachers with high occupational demands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep disorders and work-related stress often occur together and are associated with individual suffering and functional limitations as well as high economic costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet-based cognitive-behavioural therapeutic interventions for insomnia (IKVT-I) have the potential to reduce the existing gap in care and have proven to be effective in many cases. Less is known about the effectiveness of IKVT-I in populations with work-related stress.  Therefore, the aim is to evaluate an IKVT-I training specifically designed for work-related stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a two-armed, randomized controlled study (N = 126) the effects of IKVT-I training (GET.ON Regeneration) are compared to a waiting control condition before, after training and to a 6-month catamnesis. Teachers with clinically significant insomniac complaints and work-related stress reactions are included in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GET.ON Regeneration emphasizes, in addition to classic KVT-I elements (e.g. sleep restriction, examination of dysfunctional sleep-related cognitions), the mental distancing from occupational problems and the promotion of recovery activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A health economic evaluation from a societal perspective is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/geton-regeneration/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png 400w,
               /en/project/geton-regeneration/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_3201281d5628750d711e0a83c4b19c50.png 760w,
               /en/project/geton-regeneration/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/geton-regeneration/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;121&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Stress</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occupational stress is associated with numerous psychological and emotional problems, such as depression and anxiety, and can have a significant economic cost due to loss of productivity, absenteeism or incapacity to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies prove the effectiveness of traditional face-to-face training; however, it is costly and time-consuming. Online-based interventions to reduce occupational stress counteract these disadvantages, but there is little evidence to date. Persons from the general population who experience occupational stress (N=260) are randomly assigned to the intervention group (IG) or the 6-month waiting list control group in a randomized controlled trial. Participants will receive weekly feedback from an online coach on each of the 7 training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficacy will be assessed at pre- and post-trial, after 6 months, and as an extended follow-up for the IG after 12 months. Primary outcome is perceived stress. Cost effectiveness is also reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/geton-stress/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png 400w,
               /en/project/geton-stress/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_3201281d5628750d711e0a83c4b19c50.png 760w,
               /en/project/geton-stress/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/geton-stress/banner_hu540755bc102612bbafb42ec2f69893e5_89688_e97add2650279679559836f917a2fe84.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;121&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MasterMind</title>
      <link>/en/project/mastermind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/mastermind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MasterMind project aimed to make high-quality treatment methods for depression more widely available in Europe using internet and technology-based concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression targets a huge disease burden worldwide, which manifests itself in high incidence rates and enormous social costs. Technology-based treatment concepts are well researched and show high efficacy in the treatment of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the project was to evaluate the effectiveness of cCBT (computerized cognitive-behavioral therapy) in more than 10 EU countries within a large-scale project (more than 5,000 patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project identified barriers and success factors in the implementation of cCBT in different political, social, and economic contexts, and from the perspective of patients, professionals, and health care providers. On this basis, recommendations were made for the implementation of cCBT at the European level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project ran from 1 March 2014 to 28 February 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mastermind-project.eu/scientific-publications/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publications &amp;amp; Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Topics of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equal access to treatment&lt;/strong&gt;: All EU citizens suffering from depression should have equal access to evidence-based treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;: Countries and regions within the EU cooperate to exchange knowledge and optimise treatment processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusion&lt;/strong&gt;: Health professionals, healthcare providers, and patients are equally involved in the development of good treatment options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-management&lt;/strong&gt;: All patients with depression who are willing and able to do so should be given the chance to manage their mental health themselves with technical support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_2452c69bc6bba4ba3ae920e611b78091.png 400w,
               /en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_bfb54c0dc1a922842acf6bfb23da2e7e.png 760w,
               /en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_2452c69bc6bba4ba3ae920e611b78091.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;94&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
