<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandra Schlicker, DiplPsych, PP | Protect Lab</title>
    <link>/en/author/sandra-schlicker-diplpsych-pp/</link>
      <atom:link href="/en/author/sandra-schlicker-diplpsych-pp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Sandra Schlicker, DiplPsych, PP</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Protect Lab 2021</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/en/author/sandra-schlicker-diplpsych-pp/avatar_hu12dc202e3b16d0945d5ee5931dc89b1b_589243_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Sandra Schlicker, DiplPsych, PP</title>
      <link>/en/author/sandra-schlicker-diplpsych-pp/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Web- and Mobile-Based Intervention for Comorbid, Recurrent Depression in Patients With Chronic Back Pain on Sick Leave (Get.Back): Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial on Feasibility, User Satisfaction, and Effectiveness</title>
      <link>/en/publication/a-web-and-mobile-based-intervention-for-comorbid-recurrent-depression-in-patients-with-chronic-back-pain-on-sick-leave-get-back-pilot-randomized-controlled-trial-on-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/a-web-and-mobile-based-intervention-for-comorbid-recurrent-depression-in-patients-with-chronic-back-pain-on-sick-leave-get-back-pilot-randomized-controlled-trial-on-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Background&lt;/em&gt;: Chronic back pain (CBP) is linked to a higher prevalence and higher occurrence of major depressive disorder (MDD) and can lead to reduced quality of life. Unfortunately, individuals with both CBP and recurrent MDD are underidentified. Utilizing health care insurance data may provide a possibility to better identify this complex population. In addition, internet- and mobile-based interventions might enhance the availability of existing treatments and provide help to those highly burdened individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective&lt;/em&gt;: This pilot randomized controlled trial investigated the feasibility of recruitment via the health records of a German health insurance company. The study also examined user satisfaction and effectiveness of a 9-week cognitive behavioral therapy and Web- and mobile-based guided self-help intervention Get.Back in CBP patients with recurrent MDD on sick leave compared with a waitlist control condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt;: Health records from a German health insurance company were used to identify and recruit participants (N=76) via invitation letters. Study outcomes were measured using Web-based self-report assessments at baseline, posttreatment (9 weeks), and a 6-month follow-up. The primary outcome was depressive symptom severity (Center for Epidemiological Studies–Depression); secondary outcomes included anxiety (Hamilton Anxiety and Depression Scale), quality of life (Assessment of Quality of Life), pain-related variables (Oswestry Disability Index, Pain Self-Efficacy Questionnaire, and pain intensity), and negative effects (Inventory for the Assessment of Negative Effects of Psychotherapy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;: The total enrollment rate with the recruitment strategy used was 1.26% (76/6000). Participants completed 4.8 modules (SD 2.6, range 0-7) of Get.Back. The overall user satisfaction was favorable (mean Client Satisfaction Questionnaire score=24.5, SD 5.2). Covariance analyses showed a small but statistically significant reduction in depressive symptom severity in the intervention group (n=40) at posttreatment compared with the waitlist control group (n=36; F1,76=3.62, P=.03; d=0.28, 95% CI −0.17 to 0.74). Similar findings were noted for the reduction of anxiety symptoms (F1,76=10.45; P=.001; d=0.14, 95% CI −0.31 to 0.60) at posttreatment. Other secondary outcomes were nonsignificant (.06≤P≤.44). At the 6-month follow-up, the difference between the groups with regard to reduction in depressive symptom severity was no longer statistically significant (F1,76=1.50, P=.11; d=0.10, 95% CI −0.34 to 0.46). The between-group difference in anxiety at posttreatment was maintained to follow-up (F1,76=2.94, P=.04; d=0.38, 95% CI −0.07 to 0.83). There were no statistically significant differences across groups regarding other secondary outcomes at the 6-month follow-up (.08≤P≤.42).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;: These results suggest that participants with comorbid depression and CBP on sick leave may benefit from internet- and mobile-based interventions, as exemplified with the positive user satisfaction ratings. The recruitment strategy via health insurance letter invitations appeared feasible, but more research is needed to understand how response rates in untreated individuals with CBP and comorbid depression can be increased.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers and facilitators for referrals of primary care patients to blended internet-based psychotherapy for depression- A mixed methods study of general practitioners views.</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-a-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-a-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers and Facilitators for Referrals of Primary Care Patients to Blended Internet-Based Psychotherapy for Depression- Mixed Methods Study of General Practitioners’ Views</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of a Guided Internet-and Mobile-Based Intervention for Patients with Chronic Back Pain and Depression (WARD-BP)- A Multicenter  Pragmatic Randomized Controlled Trial</title>
      <link>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-and-mobile-based-intervention-for-patients-with-chronic-back-pain-and-depression-ward-bp-a-multicenter-pragmatic-randomized-controlled-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-and-mobile-based-intervention-for-patients-with-chronic-back-pain-and-depression-ward-bp-a-multicenter-pragmatic-randomized-controlled-trial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of a Guided Web-Based Self-help Intervention to Prevent Depression in Patients With Persistent Back Pain- The PROD-BP Randomized Clinical Trial</title>
      <link>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-a-guided-web-based-self-help-intervention-to-prevent-depression-in-patients-with-persistent-back-pain-the-prod-bp-randomized-clinical-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-a-guided-web-based-self-help-intervention-to-prevent-depression-in-patients-with-persistent-back-pain-the-prod-bp-randomized-clinical-trial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dried Blood Spots</title>
      <link>/en/project/dried-blood-spots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/dried-blood-spots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modification of biomarkers through an internet-based intervention for depression in back pain patients on sick leave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is a serious psychological condition that can have a devastating impact on patients, their family, friends and society. There is currently no laboratory test for this disorder, so patients often have to wait years for a diagnosis. During this time they do not receive the treatment and support they need. For this reason, we are developing a molecular test based on &amp;ldquo;Blood Spots&amp;rdquo; (i.e. dried drops of blood on filter paper). Such a test can provide an early and accurate diagnosis for patients with depression and help to get further assistance quickly. We measure the concentration of over 100 proteins in the dried blood drops. To do this, we use a technique called mass spectrometer analysis. The results of the study will be published.
​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_bae4c81deef1712e40303c825245869e.png 400w,
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_c6ef50dccb1886f16a4e144b3f73e361.png 760w,
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_bae4c81deef1712e40303c825245869e.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;92&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.Back</title>
      <link>/en/project/get-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/get-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effectiveness of a guided web-based intervention for the treatment of depression and back pain during incapacity to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back pain and depression are among the number one common diseases and are enormously stressful for those affected. Depression usually affects all areas of the patient&amp;rsquo;s life: thinking, feelings, actions, body and relationships with other people. And because it is precisely with this disease that it is so difficult to make the decision to seek help, even though the drive to change something is lacking, it is extremely important to take a new path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why an online training has been developed for people who have back pain, suffer from depressive symptoms, are currently on sick leave, and want to work on improving their mood. The following questions will be examined:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Get.Back effective for back pain patients with depression compared to standard treatment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Get.Back cost effective for back pain patients with depression compared to standard treatment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which factors moderate the effect of Get.Back?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on a two-arm, pragmatic, randomized controlled study, Get.Back aims to investigate a web-based depression intervention. Get.Back includes modules for behavioral activation, problem solving, cognitive restructuring, physical activation and relapse prevention. The program is developed for weekly treatment over a total period of nine weeks and includes stwo booster sessions two and four months after the end of treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary study outcome is depression severity at end of intervention. Secondary outcomes are: Depression remission, quality of life, pain intensity, pain-related limitation, pain-related self-efficacy, work capacity, adherence and satisfaction with the intervention, and intervention costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outlook: The present effectiveness study focuses on disability due to back pain and depression as the most common health conditions associated with high life expectancy and health care costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.barmer.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BARMER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_6e2bf0050d56d7fe291b17cc6fcc1c94.png 400w,
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_b8f812ff84836ee00aa5937edf443e1e.png 760w,
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_6e2bf0050d56d7fe291b17cc6fcc1c94.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;86&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WARD-BP</title>
      <link>/en/project/ward-bp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/ward-bp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet-based Prevention of Major Depression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major Depression (MD) is associated with a significant loss of quality of life, increased mortality rates and enormous economic costs. It is estimated that current therapies could reduce the burden of disease attributable to MD at the population level by only one third. Preventive services can help reduce the burden of disease caused by MD. The aim of the study is therefore to evaluate an internet-based intervention for the prevention of MD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: In a two-arm randomized controlled trial (N=420) the (cost-) effectiveness of an internet-based intervention (GET.ON Depression) relative to a control condition (psychoeducation) will be compared to the 12-month catamesis. The sample includes adults with subclinical depression. GET.ON Depression includes minimal therapeutic support by an online coach. The primary endpoint is the time to onset of a depressive episode. A &lt;a href=&#34;/en/health-economics/&#34;&gt;health economic evaluation&lt;/a&gt; from a societal perspective will be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bmbf.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Ministry for Education and Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_2a1a4076e4ffb17b060d8250b4bea5ea.png 400w,
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_c7f1d6fb5e7b40bab347bfc90f8a1bc9.png 760w,
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_2a1a4076e4ffb17b060d8250b4bea5ea.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;145&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Nonsuicidal Severely Depressed Individuals with Diabetes Profit from Internet-Based Guided Self-Help? Secondary Analyses of a Pragmatic Randomized Trial</title>
      <link>/en/publication/do-nonsuicidal-severely-depressed-individuals-with-diabetes-profit-from-internet-based-guided-self-help-secondary-analyses-of-a-pragmatic-randomized-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/do-nonsuicidal-severely-depressed-individuals-with-diabetes-profit-from-internet-based-guided-self-help-secondary-analyses-of-a-pragmatic-randomized-trial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of an Online Guided Self-Help Intervention for Prevention of Depression in Patients with Persistent Back Pain (PROD-BP)- A Pragmatic  Observer-Masked  Randomized </title>
      <link>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-an-online-guided-self-help-intervention-for-prevention-of-depression-in-patients-with-persistent-back-pain-prod-bp-a-pragmatic-observer-masked-randomized-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-an-online-guided-self-help-intervention-for-prevention-of-depression-in-patients-with-persistent-back-pain-prod-bp-a-pragmatic-observer-masked-randomized-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a text-message-based maintenance intervention for Major Depressive Disorder after inpatient cognitive behavioral therapy</title>
      <link>/en/publication/evaluation-of-a-text-message-based-maintenance-intervention-for-major-depressive-disorder-after-inpatient-cognitive-behavioral-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/evaluation-of-a-text-message-based-maintenance-intervention-for-major-depressive-disorder-after-inpatient-cognitive-behavioral-therapy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a guided internet-and mobile-based depression intervention for individuals with chronic back pain- protocol of a multi-centre randomised </title>
      <link>/en/publication/effectiveness-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-and-mobile-based-depression-intervention-for-individuals-with-chronic-back-pain-protocol-of-a-multi-centre-randomised-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/effectiveness-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-and-mobile-based-depression-intervention-for-individuals-with-chronic-back-pain-protocol-of-a-multi-centre-randomised-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a guided Internet-and mobile-based intervention for the indicated prevention of major depression in patients with chronic back pain </title>
      <link>/en/publication/effectiveness-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-and-mobile-based-intervention-for-the-indicated-prevention-of-major-depression-in-patients-with-chronic-back-pain-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/effectiveness-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-and-mobile-based-intervention-for-the-indicated-prevention-of-major-depression-in-patients-with-chronic-back-pain-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers to and facilitators for referral to blended internet-based depression treatment in primary care</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-to-and-facilitators-for-referral-to-blended-internet-based-depression-treatment-in-primary-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-to-and-facilitators-for-referral-to-blended-internet-based-depression-treatment-in-primary-care/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet-and mobile-based treatment of comorbid depression in chronic back pain patients on sick leave</title>
      <link>/en/publication/internet-and-mobile-based-treatment-of-comorbid-depression-in-chronic-back-pain-patients-on-sick-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/internet-and-mobile-based-treatment-of-comorbid-depression-in-chronic-back-pain-patients-on-sick-leave/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FR007 neu</title>
      <link>/en/publication/fr007-neu-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/fr007-neu-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
