<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ingrid Titzler, MSc, DiplKommWirt, PP | Protect Lab</title>
    <link>/en/author/ingrid-titzler-msc-diplkommwirt-pp/</link>
      <atom:link href="/en/author/ingrid-titzler-msc-diplkommwirt-pp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ingrid Titzler, MSc, DiplKommWirt, PP</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Protect Lab 2022</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/en/author/ingrid-titzler-msc-diplkommwirt-pp/avatar_hu321f47cfd7c53bf09b45507446fd5e61_4929886_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Ingrid Titzler, MSc, DiplKommWirt, PP</title>
      <link>/en/author/ingrid-titzler-msc-diplkommwirt-pp/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are guided internet-based interventions for the indicated prevention of depression in green professions effective in the long run? Longitudinal analysis of the 6-and 12-month </title>
      <link>/en/publication/are-guided-internet-based-interventions-for-the-indicated-prevention-of-depression-in-green-professions-effective-in-the-long-run-longitudinal-analysis-of-the-6-and-12-month-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/are-guided-internet-based-interventions-for-the-indicated-prevention-of-depression-in-green-professions-effective-in-the-long-run-longitudinal-analysis-of-the-6-and-12-month-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telefonisches Einzelfallcoaching als Präventionsangebot für Landwirte  Förster und Gartenbauer?-Ergebnisse einer randomisiert-kontrollierten Wirksamkeitsstudie (TEC-A)</title>
      <link>/en/publication/telefonisches-einzelfallcoaching-als-praventionsangebot-fur-landwirte-forster-und-gartenbauer-ergebnisse-einer-randomisiert-kontrollierten-wirksamkeitsstudie-tec-a-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/telefonisches-einzelfallcoaching-als-praventionsangebot-fur-landwirte-forster-und-gartenbauer-ergebnisse-einer-randomisiert-kontrollierten-wirksamkeitsstudie-tec-a-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers and facilitators for referrals of primary care patients to blended internet-based psychotherapy for depression- A mixed methods study of general practitioners views.</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-a-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-a-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers and Facilitators for Referrals of Primary Care Patients to Blended Internet-Based Psychotherapy for Depression- Mixed Methods Study of General Practitioners’ Views</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-referrals-of-primary-care-patients-to-blended-internet-based-psychotherapy-for-depression-mixed-methods-study-of-general-practitioners-views/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and cost-effectiveness of a guided internet-based Acceptance and Commitment Therapy to improve chronic pain–related disability in green professions (PACT-A)- study </title>
      <link>/en/publication/clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-based-acceptance-and-commitment-therapy-to-improve-chronic-pain-related-disability-in-green-professions-pact-a-study-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-based-acceptance-and-commitment-therapy-to-improve-chronic-pain-related-disability-in-green-professions-pact-a-study-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of guided internet-based interventions in the indicated prevention of depression in green professions (PROD-A)- Results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial</title>
      <link>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-guided-internet-based-interventions-in-the-indicated-prevention-of-depression-in-green-professions-prod-a-results-of-a-pragmatic-randomized-controlled-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/effectiveness-of-guided-internet-based-interventions-in-the-indicated-prevention-of-depression-in-green-professions-prod-a-results-of-a-pragmatic-randomized-controlled-trial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing internet-and tele-based interventions to prevent mental health disorders in farmers  foresters and gardeners (ImplementIT)- study protocol for the multi-level </title>
      <link>/en/publication/implementing-internet-and-tele-based-interventions-to-prevent-mental-health-disorders-in-farmers-foresters-and-gardeners-implementit-study-protocol-for-the-multi-level-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/implementing-internet-and-tele-based-interventions-to-prevent-mental-health-disorders-in-farmers-foresters-and-gardeners-implementit-study-protocol-for-the-multi-level-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol- Clinical and cost-effectiveness of a guided internet-based Acceptance and Commitment Therapy to improve chronic pain–related disability in green professions (PACT-A </title>
      <link>/en/publication/protocol-clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-based-acceptance-and-commitment-therapy-to-improve-chronic-pain-related-disability-in-green-professions-pact-a-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/protocol-clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-a-guided-internet-based-acceptance-and-commitment-therapy-to-improve-chronic-pain-related-disability-in-green-professions-pact-a-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Compared</title>
      <link>/en/project/e-compared/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/e-compared/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is one of the most common and serious diseases of our time. Currently, about four million people in Germany suffer from the symptoms, but only a few receive effective treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet-based forms of treatment can be a possible supplement to classic therapy concepts. These promise a lower uptake threshold, reduced waiting times and help independent of time and place. Numerous studies show that these forms of treatment can be successful in depression. However, not all patients are interested in and/or suitable for a purely internet-supported treatment. Combined procedures that combine psychotherapy on site and internet-supported treatment elements could use the advantages of both approaches and be a promising supplement to classic forms of therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against this background, the Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy of the FAU is investigating the effectiveness of such a combined depression treatment (online lessons on website, smartphone app, personal therapy conversations on site in Erlangen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruitment in general practitioners&#39; practices within the RCT study took place from February 2015 to August 2016. We are currently not enrolling any more patients in the study. The treatment phase of &amp;ldquo;Moodbuster&amp;rdquo; will be completed in early 2017 for the last patient enrolled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scientific-background&#34;&gt;Scientific background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-COMPARED (European-COMPARative Effectiveness research on online depression) is an interdisciplinary project involving specialists from the fields of psychology, health technology, communication and information technology and health care. The original project period from 01.01.2014 to 31.12.2016 has been extended by another 6 months until 30.06.2017. The project compares the standard treatment of depression in eight European countries with a combination of personal (face-to-face) and web- or mobile-based therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evaluation will use randomized controlled trials (RCT), advanced ICT (information and communication technology) platforms, technological intelligence and an economic prediction model to investigate which form of treatment is more effective, for which patient group and under which conditions. In Germany, the evaluation study was implemented in primary health care and thus in the setting of the outpatient treatment of depressive patients in GP practice. For this purpose, close cooperation with GP practices in the Erlangen-Nuremberg-Fürth metropolitan region took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cooperating-gp-practices-in-the-metropolitan-region-erlangen-nuremberg-fürth&#34;&gt;Cooperating GP practices in the metropolitan region Erlangen-Nuremberg-Fürth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank the GP practices who, as cooperation partners, have been able to support the study and win over their affected patients to participate in the study on the treatment of depressive symptoms. Flyers and posters for the waiting room and the personal doctor-patient consultation were made available to the GPs for the recruitment of patients in the GP practices. The time spent by the general practitioners involved in the study was to be a maximum of 30-60 minutes per patient and was compensated. By participating in the study, family doctors&#39; practices are making an important contribution to the further development of depression treatment in Germany. In addition, their patients benefited from a prompt start of treatment; i.e. therapy places were available without waiting time. An overview of the cooperating GP practices can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psych1.phil.uni-erlangen.de/forschung/internetbasierte-therapie/e-compared_hausrztliche_kooperationspartner_2016.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-research-project-for-depressive-patients-in-family-practice&#34;&gt;The research project for depressive patients in family practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients affected by depressive symptoms could contact their own family doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice, as any family doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice could start a cooperation with us at any time. By answering a health questionnaire (by post or online) patients registered with us and subsequently received further information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conditions-of-participation&#34;&gt;Conditions of participation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients who were at least 18 years old and were not undergoing any current psychotherapeutic treatment by psychologists or doctors were eligible to participate in the study. Previous therapeutic experience or an existing or concurrent drug treatment was allowed. Another prerequisite for participation was the diagnosis of major depression (mild, moderate or severe; also chronic courses or relapses). Patients with the diagnosis of a minor depression were referred to a depression prevention study by us. The diagnosis was carried out by our test directors (telephone interview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to participate in our study, the treating family doctor&amp;rsquo;s practice had to already be a cooperation partner of ours or show willingness to become one. In order to participate in the internet-supported therapy modules, a computer with internet access was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The project was awarded the Erlanger Medizinpreis in 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Union&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_0a6daedd5d42b552fd5eb150f074859b.png 400w,
               /en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_0ae680500a00e1d62804ae75d5c51b31.png 760w,
               /en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/e-compared/banner_hu82f5d6c71446a8fca09a398ab3fc1fe3_16206_0a6daedd5d42b552fd5eb150f074859b.png&#34;
               width=&#34;122&#34;
               height=&#34;82&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Balance With Us</title>
      <link>/en/project/mit-uns-im-gleichgewicht/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/mit-uns-im-gleichgewicht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental disorder prevention with Internet- and telephone-based interventions for persons in the &amp;ldquo;green professions &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model project &amp;ldquo;Mit uns im Gleichgewicht&amp;rdquo; (In Balance With Us), funded by the Social Insurance for Agriculture, Forestry and Horticulture (SVLFG), aims to promote and maintain mental health among farmers, foresters and horticulturists and is being scientifically evaluated by the Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-Nuremberg and the University of Ulm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain and promote the mental health of farmers, foresters and horticulturists, the SVLFG offers the insured persons on-site preventive measures such as seminars on stress management. Within the framework of the model project, these offers will be expanded to include internet and tele-based interventions (online health training by the GET.ON Institute and intensive individual coaching by IVPNetworks). Interventions to prevent mental stress are particularly in demand in agriculture, as this occupational group is exposed to many stressors and strains due to difficult working conditions (e.g. high workload, family conflicts, seasonal work). It has been proven that internet and tele-based interventions can be effective, but the effects at population level depend on the actual use of the target group. With this background, there is a great need for scientifically sound knowledge about the needs of farmers, foresters and horticulturists, their partners and family members working with them, and how these needs can be met effectively. In addition, it should be examined whether target group-specific offers for this group of people can effectively and cost-effectively counteract the development of depressive disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy of the FAU, on behalf of SVLFG, is investigating in partly overlapping sub-projects the current use and acceptance of preventive interventions among farmers, gardeners and foresters on the one hand, and the effectiveness of two specific interventions (online-based health training, telemedical intensive care) on the other hand. In addition, the new health services and online-based interventions are being offered to SVLFG insured persons via different access routes as part of a large implementation study throughout Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target group of the project&lt;/strong&gt;
Farmers insured with SVLFG, their co-insured partners and family members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project duration&lt;/strong&gt;
01.06.2017 – 30.05.2021&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blended Psychotherapy- Treatment Concept and Case Report for the Integration of Internet-and Mobile-Based Interventions into Brief Psychotherapy of Depressive Disorders</title>
      <link>/en/publication/blended-psychotherapy-treatment-concept-and-case-report-for-the-integration-of-internet-and-mobile-based-interventions-into-brief-psychotherapy-of-depressive-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/blended-psychotherapy-treatment-concept-and-case-report-for-the-integration-of-internet-and-mobile-based-interventions-into-brief-psychotherapy-of-depressive-disorders/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blended Psychotherapy–verzahnte Psychotherapie- Behandlungskonzept und Fallbericht zur Integration von Internet-und Mobil-basierten Interventionen in die Kurzzeittherapie von </title>
      <link>/en/publication/blended-psychotherapy-verzahnte-psychotherapie-behandlungskonzept-und-fallbericht-zur-integration-von-internet-und-mobil-basierten-interventionen-in-die-kurzzeittherapie-von-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/blended-psychotherapy-verzahnte-psychotherapie-behandlungskonzept-und-fallbericht-zur-integration-von-internet-und-mobil-basierten-interventionen-in-die-kurzzeittherapie-von-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and cost-effectiveness of guided internet-based interventions in the indicated prevention of depression in green professions (PROD-A)- study protocol of a 36-month </title>
      <link>/en/publication/clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-guided-internet-based-interventions-in-the-indicated-prevention-of-depression-in-green-professions-prod-a-study-protocol-of-a-36-month-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-guided-internet-based-interventions-in-the-indicated-prevention-of-depression-in-green-professions-prod-a-study-protocol-of-a-36-month-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and cost-effectiveness of personalized tele-based coaching for farmers  foresters and gardeners to prevent depression- Study protocol of an 18-month follow-up </title>
      <link>/en/publication/clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-personalized-tele-based-coaching-for-farmers-foresters-and-gardeners-to-prevent-depression-study-protocol-of-an-18-month-follow-up-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/clinical-and-cost-effectiveness-of-personalized-tele-based-coaching-for-farmers-foresters-and-gardeners-to-prevent-depression-study-protocol-of-an-18-month-follow-up-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementierung internet-und telefongestützter Präventionsmaßnahmen (ImpleMentIT) in ländlichen Betrieben der Land-/Forstwirtschaft und Gartenbau- Studienprotokoll für die </title>
      <link>/en/publication/implementierung-internet-und-telefongestutzter-praventionsma%C3%9Fnahmen-implementit-in-landlichen-betrieben-der-land-forstwirtschaft-und-gartenbau-studienprotokoll-fur-die-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/implementierung-internet-und-telefongestutzter-praventionsma%C3%9Fnahmen-implementit-in-landlichen-betrieben-der-land-forstwirtschaft-und-gartenbau-studienprotokoll-fur-die-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wahrgenommener Stress und Lebensqualität nach einem telefonischen Einzelfallcoaching für Agrarberufen (TEC-A)- erste Ergebnisse einer randomisiert-kontrollierten Wirksamkeitsstudie</title>
      <link>/en/publication/wahrgenommener-stress-und-lebensqualitat-nach-einem-telefonischen-einzelfallcoaching-fur-agrarberufen-tec-a-erste-ergebnisse-einer-randomisiert-kontrollierten-wirksamkeitsstudie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/wahrgenommener-stress-und-lebensqualitat-nach-einem-telefonischen-einzelfallcoaching-fur-agrarberufen-tec-a-erste-ergebnisse-einer-randomisiert-kontrollierten-wirksamkeitsstudie/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers and facilitators for the implementation of blended psychotherapy for depression- A qualitative pilot study of therapists perspective</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-the-implementation-of-blended-psychotherapy-for-depression-a-qualitative-pilot-study-of-therapists-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-and-facilitators-for-the-implementation-of-blended-psychotherapy-for-depression-a-qualitative-pilot-study-of-therapists-perspective/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a text-message-based maintenance intervention for Major Depressive Disorder after inpatient cognitive behavioral therapy</title>
      <link>/en/publication/evaluation-of-a-text-message-based-maintenance-intervention-for-major-depressive-disorder-after-inpatient-cognitive-behavioral-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/evaluation-of-a-text-message-based-maintenance-intervention-for-major-depressive-disorder-after-inpatient-cognitive-behavioral-therapy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MasterMind</title>
      <link>/en/project/mastermind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/mastermind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MasterMind project aimed to make high-quality treatment methods for depression more widely available in Europe using internet and technology-based concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression targets a huge disease burden worldwide, which manifests itself in high incidence rates and enormous social costs. Technology-based treatment concepts are well researched and show high efficacy in the treatment of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the project was to evaluate the effectiveness of cCBT (computerized cognitive-behavioral therapy) in more than 10 EU countries within a large-scale project (more than 5,000 patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project identified barriers and success factors in the implementation of cCBT in different political, social, and economic contexts, and from the perspective of patients, professionals, and health care providers. On this basis, recommendations were made for the implementation of cCBT at the European level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project ran from 1 March 2014 to 28 February 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mastermind-project.eu/scientific-publications/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publications &amp;amp; Deliverables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Topics of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equal access to treatment&lt;/strong&gt;: All EU citizens suffering from depression should have equal access to evidence-based treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;: Countries and regions within the EU cooperate to exchange knowledge and optimise treatment processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusion&lt;/strong&gt;: Health professionals, healthcare providers, and patients are equally involved in the development of good treatment options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-management&lt;/strong&gt;: All patients with depression who are willing and able to do so should be given the chance to manage their mental health themselves with technical support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_2452c69bc6bba4ba3ae920e611b78091.png 400w,
               /en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_bfb54c0dc1a922842acf6bfb23da2e7e.png 760w,
               /en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/mastermind/banner_hu61a8cc4e810cbfba5dabd5f0e1aae942_115607_2452c69bc6bba4ba3ae920e611b78091.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;94&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers to and facilitators for referral to blended internet-based depression treatment in primary care</title>
      <link>/en/publication/barriers-to-and-facilitators-for-referral-to-blended-internet-based-depression-treatment-in-primary-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/barriers-to-and-facilitators-for-referral-to-blended-internet-based-depression-treatment-in-primary-care/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FR007 neu</title>
      <link>/en/publication/fr007-neu-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/publication/fr007-neu-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
