<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christina Schulte, MSc | Protect Lab</title>
    <link>/en/author/christina-schulte-msc/</link>
      <atom:link href="/en/author/christina-schulte-msc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Christina Schulte, MSc</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Protect Lab 2023</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/en/author/christina-schulte-msc/avatar_hu054281085d3bc261e6c5ff998d80dc31_632730_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Christina Schulte, MSc</title>
      <link>/en/author/christina-schulte-msc/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>StAR</title>
      <link>/en/project/star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development and Evaluation of an online- and mobile based Intervention for adolescents and young adults with PTSD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PTSD is a mental disorder, which can occur after witnessing a traumatic event. The disorder can affect  emotional, physical, social as well as academic development. It&amp;rsquo;s consequences can, especially for children, adolescents, and young adults, extend into adulthood. The elevated distress, the possible psychological implications, educational difficulties as well as possible long-term suffering within the disorder can result in a high burden on an individual as well as on a societal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are effective treatments for PTSD in adolescents and young adults, not every person affected receives treatment offering due to structural as well as attitudinal barriers. Internet- and mobile-based interventions can help fill this health care gap. But they do not yet exist for adolescents and young adults so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project StAR aims to fill this research- as well as the health care gap, in developing an internet- and mobile-based Intervention for adolescents and young adults with PTSD and evaluating it in a feasibility study. A subsequent randomized controlled trial aims at determining its efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StAR is a subproject in the research association BestForCan. BestForCan aims at disseminating a special psychotherapeutic intervention for children, adolescents, and young adults after child abuse and neglect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_ee96c4f2b625e9e08e5927806375e8c5.png 400w,
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_41659f3d5883de3b3d423ba65a023caf.png 760w,
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_ee96c4f2b625e9e08e5927806375e8c5.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;79&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
