<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laufend | Protect Lab</title>
    <link>/en/tag/laufend/</link>
      <atom:link href="/en/tag/laufend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Laufend</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Protect Lab 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Laufend</title>
      <link>/en/tag/laufend/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSYCHOnlineTHERAPIE</title>
      <link>/en/project/psychonlinetherapie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/psychonlinetherapie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSYCHOnlineTHERAPY investigates the integration of online interventions into routine psychotherapy for patients with depressive and anxiety disorders. With the aim of improving psychotherapeutic care, the project implements and evaluates a new form of treatment, so-called blended therapy, which is a combination of online-based treatment components and outpatient psychotherapy sessions. Blended therapy has the potential to improve psychotherapeutic care, as the combination of outpatient psychotherapy with online-based treatment components enables a more flexible way of delivering therapy. Other advantages are an improved transfer of therapy content into the everyday life of the patients and an increase in the capacities of psychotherapists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the PSYCHOnlineTHERAPY project, blended psychotherapy will be evaluated in two variants and compared to standard routine care psychotherapy in a three-armed cluster-randomized controlled non-inferiority study. Psychotherapy sessions in all three study conditions comprise cognitive behavioral therapy with outpatient psychotherapists. The two variants of blended psychotherapy differ in the flexibility of the sequence and amount of psychotherapy sessions and online-based treatment components that patients additionally complete between therapy sessions. Therapists can assign the online-based treatment components individually according to the needs of their patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific evaluation of the project includes both quantitative and qualitative assessments at multiple times of measurement. The two variants of blended psychotherapy are evaluated for their effectiveness, cost-effectiveness, acceptability, and feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovationsfonds des Gemeinsamen Bundesausschusses zu neuen Versorgungsformen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StAR</title>
      <link>/en/project/star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development and Evaluation of an online- and mobile based Intervention for adolescents and young adults with PTSD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PTSD is a mental disorder, which can occur after witnessing a traumatic event. The disorder can affect  emotional, physical, social as well as academic development. It&amp;rsquo;s consequences can, especially for children, adolescents, and young adults, extend into adulthood. The elevated distress, the possible psychological implications, educational difficulties as well as possible long-term suffering within the disorder can result in a high burden on an individual as well as on a societal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are effective treatments for PTSD in adolescents and young adults, not every person affected receives treatment offering due to structural as well as attitudinal barriers. Internet- and mobile-based interventions can help fill this health care gap. But they do not yet exist for adolescents and young adults so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project StAR aims to fill this research- as well as the health care gap, in developing an internet- and mobile-based Intervention for adolescents and young adults with PTSD and evaluating it in a feasibility study. A subsequent randomized controlled trial aims at determining its efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StAR is a subproject in the research association BestForCan. BestForCan aims at disseminating a special psychotherapeutic intervention for children, adolescents, and young adults after child abuse and neglect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_ee96c4f2b625e9e08e5927806375e8c5.png 400w,
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_41659f3d5883de3b3d423ba65a023caf.png 760w,
               /en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/star/banner_hu2213d06647aa419f259d11128a87524b_134352_ee96c4f2b625e9e08e5927806375e8c5.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;79&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dried Blood Spots</title>
      <link>/en/project/dried-blood-spots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/dried-blood-spots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modification of biomarkers through an internet-based intervention for depression in back pain patients on sick leave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is a serious psychological condition that can have a devastating impact on patients, their family, friends and society. There is currently no laboratory test for this disorder, so patients often have to wait years for a diagnosis. During this time, they do not receive the treatment and support they need. For this reason, we are developing a molecular test based on &amp;ldquo;Blood Spots&amp;rdquo; (i.e. dried drops of blood on filter paper). Such a test can provide an early and accurate diagnosis for patients with depression and help to get further assistance quickly. We measure the concentration of over 100 proteins in the dried blood drops. To do this, we use a technique called mass spectrometer analysis. The results of the study will be published.
​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_bae4c81deef1712e40303c825245869e.png 400w,
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_c6ef50dccb1886f16a4e144b3f73e361.png 760w,
               /en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/dried-blood-spots/banner_hu86dceecea39595516cd5b00cae30ff93_69706_bae4c81deef1712e40303c825245869e.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;92&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.Back</title>
      <link>/en/project/get-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/get-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effectiveness of a guided web-based intervention for the treatment of depression and back pain during incapacity to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back pain and depression are among the number one common diseases and are enormously stressful for those affected. Depression usually affects all areas of the patient&amp;rsquo;s life: thinking, feelings, actions, body and relationships with other people. And because it is precisely with this disease that it is so difficult to make the decision to seek help, even though the drive to change something is lacking, it is extremely important to take a new path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why an online training has been developed for people who have back pain, suffer from depressive symptoms, are currently on sick leave, and want to work on improving their mood. The following questions will be examined:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Get.Back effective for back pain patients with depression compared to standard treatment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Get.Back cost effective for back pain patients with depression compared to standard treatment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which factors moderate the effect of Get.Back?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on a two-arm, pragmatic, randomized controlled study, Get.Back aims to investigate a web-based depression intervention. Get.Back includes modules for behavioral activation, problem solving, cognitive restructuring, physical activation and relapse prevention. The program is developed for weekly treatment over a total period of nine weeks and includes stwo booster sessions two and four months after the end of treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary study outcome is depression severity at end of intervention. Secondary outcomes are: Depression remission, quality of life, pain intensity, pain-related limitation, pain-related self-efficacy, work capacity, adherence and satisfaction with the intervention, and intervention costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outlook: The present effectiveness study focuses on disability due to back pain and depression as the most common health conditions associated with high life expectancy and health care costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.barmer.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BARMER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_6e2bf0050d56d7fe291b17cc6fcc1c94.png 400w,
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_b8f812ff84836ee00aa5937edf443e1e.png 760w,
               /en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/get-back/banner_hube3c8ba518cb608681bddc468745838f_84395_6e2bf0050d56d7fe291b17cc6fcc1c94.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;86&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICare Prevent</title>
      <link>/en/project/icare-prevent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/icare-prevent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental stress is not uncommon. Many people suffer from low spirits, worries, fears, or feel a general sense of dissatisfaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7-week online training ICare Prevent provides help in dealing with such feelings and offers background information on how they arise. In addition, the training aims to improve mental well-being and reduce mental discomfort through systematic training of helpful and proven strategies such as problem solving and activity planning to strengthen important areas of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online training ICare Prevent is currently being evaluated in a multicenter study in cooperation with universities in Germany, Switzerland, the Netherlands, Spain and Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICare Prevent is part of the EU-funded Horizon 2020 program, which has set itself the goal of developing, implementing and evaluating online training for the prevention and treatment of mental disorders in order to improve existing care structures, open new access routes and overcome implementation barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-coordination&#34;&gt;Project Coordination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the direction of Dr. David Ebert, Prof. Dr. Thomas Berger and PD Dr. Michael Schaub, one focus of our research at the Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy (KliPs) at the University of Erlangen-Nuremberg and at the Universities of Bern and Zurich is the development and scientific investigation of online programs in various areas, such as depression, anxiety disorders, stress management, sleep disorders, alcohol abuse and procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promotion--cooperation&#34;&gt;Promotion &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICare Prevent is a cooperation project within the framework of the ICare - Integrating Technology into Mental Health Care Delivery in Europe project. ICare Prevent received funding within the Horizon2020 research and innovation program of the European Union (Grant agreement No 634757).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICare project aims to establish an innovative, comprehensive mental health care delivery model in Europe. It combines evidence-based prevention, early detection and treatment of common mental disorders via a common online platform. In cooperation with established health care providers, ICare will complement or be integrated into existing services in order to avoid and reduce long-term costs caused by mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project partners come from a total of six European countries (Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Great Britain, Netherlands, Spain). All project partners have many years of research experience in the field of e-mental health. Together they can present a portfolio of more than 30 evidence-based online programmes for the promotion of mental health and for prevention, self-help, treatment and aftercare of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://icareprevent.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;banner.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Balance With Us</title>
      <link>/en/project/mit-uns-im-gleichgewicht/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/mit-uns-im-gleichgewicht/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental disorder prevention with Internet- and telephone-based interventions for persons in the &amp;ldquo;green professions &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model project &amp;ldquo;Mit uns im Gleichgewicht&amp;rdquo; (In Balance With Us), funded by the Social Insurance for Agriculture, Forestry and Horticulture (SVLFG), aims to promote and maintain mental health among farmers, foresters and horticulturists and is being scientifically evaluated by the Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-Nuremberg and the University of Ulm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain and promote the mental health of farmers, foresters and horticulturists, the SVLFG offers the insured persons on-site preventive measures such as seminars on stress management. Within the framework of the model project, these offers will be expanded to include internet and tele-based interventions (online health training by the GET.ON Institute and intensive individual coaching by IVPNetworks). Interventions to prevent mental stress are particularly in demand in agriculture, as this occupational group is exposed to many stressors and strains due to difficult working conditions (e.g. high workload, family conflicts, seasonal work). It has been proven that internet and tele-based interventions can be effective, but the effects at population level depend on the actual use of the target group. With this background, there is a great need for scientifically sound knowledge about the needs of farmers, foresters and horticulturists, their partners and family members working with them, and how these needs can be met effectively. In addition, it should be examined whether target group-specific offers for this group of people can effectively and cost-effectively counteract the development of depressive disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chair of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy of the FAU, on behalf of SVLFG, is investigating in partly overlapping sub-projects the current use and acceptance of preventive interventions among farmers, gardeners and foresters on the one hand, and the effectiveness of two specific interventions (online-based health training, telemedical intensive care) on the other hand. In addition, the new health services and online-based interventions are being offered to SVLFG insured persons via different access routes as part of a large implementation study throughout Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target group of the project&lt;/strong&gt;
Farmers insured with SVLFG, their co-insured partners and family members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project duration&lt;/strong&gt;
01.06.2017 – 30.05.2021&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paivina-Care</title>
      <link>/en/project/paivina-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/paivina-care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paivina-Care is an online-based self-help training that is specially designed to meet the needs of women with Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder. The training is offered free of charge as part of a scientific study at the Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuremberg (FAU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder is also known as vaginismus or dyspareunia. Women with Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder suffer from difficulties and pain during vaginal insertion, so that sexual intercourse is no longer possible for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genito-Pelvic Pain-Penetration Disorder is a combination of two different diagnoses of female sexual dysfunction. The new diagnosis includes both symptoms of sexual pain disorder (dyspareunia) and penetration disorder (vaginismus).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WARD-BP</title>
      <link>/en/project/ward-bp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/ward-bp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet-based Prevention of Major Depression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major Depression (MD) is associated with a significant loss of quality of life, increased mortality rates and enormous economic costs. It is estimated that current therapies could reduce the burden of disease attributable to MD at the population level by only one third. Preventive services can help reduce the burden of disease caused by MD. The aim of the study is therefore to evaluate an internet-based intervention for the prevention of MD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: In a two-arm randomized controlled trial (N=420) the (cost-) effectiveness of an internet-based intervention (GET.ON Depression) relative to a control condition (psychoeducation) will be compared to the 12-month catamesis. The sample includes adults with subclinical depression. GET.ON Depression includes minimal therapeutic support by an online coach. The primary endpoint is the time to onset of a depressive episode. A &lt;a href=&#34;/en/health-economics/&#34;&gt;health economic evaluation&lt;/a&gt; from a societal perspective will be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;funding--cooperation&#34;&gt;Funding &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bmbf.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Ministry for Education and Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_2a1a4076e4ffb17b060d8250b4bea5ea.png 400w,
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_c7f1d6fb5e7b40bab347bfc90f8a1bc9.png 760w,
               /en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_3.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/en/project/ward-bp/banner_hu1db7035f83b3ff99b95487efc54ac5dc_98957_2a1a4076e4ffb17b060d8250b4bea5ea.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;145&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get.On Offline</title>
      <link>/en/project/geton-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/geton-offline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GET.On Offline is an online-based self-help training for coping with problematic internet usage. Problematic Internet usage can relate to computer games, social networks, but also to online sex, online shopping and online gambling. Where is the line between everyday use and problematic use? Problematic behavior begins when affected persons have an irresistible desire for the respective activities. Their thoughts and emotions are massively influenced by online offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who use the Internet excessively begin to lose control over their use and, if they are denied access, withdrawal symptoms may occur. This can manifest itself, for example, in restlessness, nervousness or depressive mood. Tolerance can also develop and other important areas of life can be affected. Problematic Internet use thus has negative consequences in various areas. One may no longer pay attention to a healthy lifestyle or experience losses in professional or academic areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geton-training.de/internetsucht-php/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Study Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;hek.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImpleMentAll</title>
      <link>/en/project/implementall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/implementall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;projektbeschreibung&#34;&gt;Projektbeschreibung&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In den letzten zwei Jahrzehnten wurden große Anstrengungen in die Entwicklung, Testung und Implementation von eHealth für eine weite Bandbreite von Gesundheitsproblemen, im körperlichen wie im psychischen Bereich gesetzt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nichtsdestotrotz schaffen es wenige Interventionen in die Routinebehandlung, oder benötigen viele Jahre auf dem Weg dahin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ImpleMentAll (IMA) zielt darauf ab, durch die Entwicklung, Anwendung und Evaluation maßgeschneiderter Implementationsstrategien in einem natürlichen Labor derzeitiger eHealth-Implementationsintiviativen in der EU und darüber hinaus eine evidenzbasierte Antwort auf dieses Problem zu geben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Forschung des Projektes baut dabei auf vorhergegangenen internationalen Projekten auf (z.B. &lt;a href=&#34;https://renewinghealth.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Renewing Health&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.e-compared.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;E-COMPARED&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastermind-project.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MasterMind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.implementall.eu/16-npt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NPT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.implementall.eu/17-nomad.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NoMAD&lt;/a&gt;, und &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.implementall.eu/18-mast.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MAST&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die laufenden Implementations-Initiativen, die die Basis für die Implementationforschung dieses Projektes bilden, basieren sämtlich auf internet-basierter kognitiver Verhaltenstherapie (iCBT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICBT-Implementationsprozesse werden derzeit auf der ganzen Welt durchgeführt. ImpleMentAll nutzt diese Projekte, um Werkzeuge zur Implementation von iCBT zu entwerfen, die eHealth effizienter machen sollen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ziele-des-projekts&#34;&gt;Ziele des Projekts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entwicklung eines generischen &amp;ldquo;Integrated Theory&amp;rdquo;-basierten Rahmens für Interventions-Anpassungen (ItFits-toolkit) zur datenbasierten Implementation evidenzbasierter eHealth-Dienstleistungen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstration der Vorteile des ItFits-toolkit auf die Implementation von eHealth für psychische Störungen (iCBT) in 9 europäischen Ländern und Australien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dissemination des validierten Toolkits in verschiedenen Kontexten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StudiCare</title>
      <link>/en/project/studicare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/project/studicare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mental-health-promotion-in-college-students&#34;&gt;Mental Health Promotion in College Students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StudiCare includes various online training courses for the prevention and treatment of mental illness, tailored to the needs of college students. In order to improve existing offers, the StudiCare panel regularly surveys undergraduate students at the Friedrich-Alexander-University and the University of Ulm about their mental well-being from the first semester onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College is a new stage of life in which students make the transition from adolescence to adulthood. This transition period is characterized by joyful experiences as well as new, stressful situations. These include, for example, looking for one&amp;rsquo;s own apartment, organizing finances and studies, finding new friends, getting used to a new environment, exam stress, etc. In the course of their studies, students are not only confronted with this new situation, but may also experience crises. In combination with possible risk behaviors, such as excessive consumption of alcohol or cannabis, this can lead to exhaustion, psychosomatic complaints, anxiety and depressive disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;studicare-panel&#34;&gt;StudiCare Panel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web-based panel survey is conducted in numerous countries worldwide as part of the WHO The World Mental Health Survey Initiative under the coordination of Harvard University among students from the first semester onwards. The aim of the survey is to obtain information on the mental health of students as well as on risk and protective factors for emotional stress during their undergraduate studies. In addition, more information on the willingness and barriers to using psychosocial interventions and counseling services will be collected. With information from the surveys, the need for help and support services will be assessed, existing counseling services will be improved and new online-based interventions tailored to the individual needs of students will be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;studicare-online-health-trainings&#34;&gt;StudiCare Online Health Trainings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online health training courses from StudiCare are low-threshold structured self-help training courses. These trainings can improve the well-being of students and alleviate complaints in a wide variety of areas. They can be used independently of time and place, can be optimally integrated into the individual daily routine and can be conducted anonymously. In the training courses, students manage their complaints independently by working through numerous modules. Modules are based on cognitive-behavioral techniques that are also used in conventional psychotherapy. Essential here are various practical exercises such as relaxation techniques, protocols for self-observation and the integration of small exercises into everyday life (&amp;ldquo;tiny task&amp;rdquo;). These help to reduce negative behavior and build up positive behavior. In the course of the project, new trainings are continuously being developed that deal with topics that are relevant for students. The newly developed online health trainings will be examined in randomized clinical studies to evaluate their effectiveness and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.studicare.com&#34;&gt;Training Participation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evidence-based-methods-for-promoting-mental-health-among-students-series-of-meta-analytical-reviews&#34;&gt;Evidence-based methods for promoting mental health among students: Series of meta-analytical reviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to derive appropriate measures, a comprehensive assessment of the current evidence base of psychosocial support services is necessary. In a series of meta-analytical reviews, the current knowledge about effective psychological treatment and prevention services including their effectiveness is collected and critically examined. Psychological interventions and their effectiveness are examined with regard to specific disorder areas (e.g. anxiety symptoms, eating disorders, sleep disorders, suicidal tendencies) or intervention methods (e.g. internet-based procedures, &amp;ldquo;third wave&amp;rdquo; procedures). Along with clinical effectiveness, special attention is devoted to the influence of interventions on the academic impairment of students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promotion--cooperation&#34;&gt;Promotion &amp;amp; Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARMER, Bergische Universität Wuppertal, European Union, FernUniversität in Hagen,
FOM University, Harvard Medical School, Leuphana University of Lüneburg, Minddistrict, RWTH Aachen University,
University Jaume I, University of Ulm, University of Zurich, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam,
World Health Organization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;logos.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;501&#34;/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
